Guide to the Bernhard Knollenberg Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence (Chronological), 1560-1943; Series I; 5.5 linear feet (13 Boxes)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; bands playing all day long, 1864 July 3 (Box 11, Folder 990)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; description of march and battle, 1864 July 11 (Box 11, Folder 991)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; diary--discussion of what and why writing, 1864 July 13 (Box 11, Folder 992)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; unpleasant weather conditions, 1864 July 15 (Box 11, Folder 993)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Lucy Curtiss; unreal nature of killing, 1864 July 17 (Box 11, Folder 994)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; encounter with rebels, 1864 July 19 (Box 11, Folder 995)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; in hospital, 1864 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 996)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; lack of knowledge about sickness, 1864 August 20 (Box 11, Folder 997)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; health improving, 1864 August 22 (Box 11, Folder 998)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; series of letters written continuously from hospital concerning improving health, 1864 October 18-October 31 (Box 11, Folder 999)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; transferred to soldiers' "home.", 1864 November 3 (Box 11, Folder 1000)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; transfer back to company, 1864 November 6 (Box 11, Folder 1001)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; travels in Virginia, 1864 November 9 (Box 11, Folder 1002)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Mackenzie replacement, 1864 November 15 (Box 11, Folder 1003)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; reconnaissance detail, 1864 November 17 (Box 11, Folder 1004)
  - ALS, Homer Curtis to Fannie Curtiss; rations brought by train, 1864 November 18 (Box 11, Folder 1005)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; uncertainty about future, 1864 November 30 (Box 11, Folder 1006)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; trip on steamer "Massachusetts.", 1864 December 3 (Box 11, Folder 1007)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; visit with friends, 1864 December 6 (Box 11, Folder 1008)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; description of troops' activities, 1864 December 11 (Box 11, Folder 1009)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; Thomas' victory over Hood, 1864 December 19 (Box 11, Folder 1010)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; transcription of Muster rolls, 1864 December 28 (Box 11, Folder 1011)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to John Dalzell; regarding public land, 1864 December 29 (Box 11, Folder 1012)
  - ADS, Recommendation for furlough for William Johnson by citizens of Warren, Conn, 1864 December 30 (Box 11, Folder 1013)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; stationed in new company, 1865 January 15 (Box 11, Folder 1014)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; busy activities as member of staff, 1865 January 17 (Box 11, Folder 1015)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; order for pair of boots, 1864 January 22 (Box 11, Folder 1016)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sister [?]; prospective discharge, 1865 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 1017)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Starr tragedy, 1865 January 30 (Box 11, Folder 1018)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; orders to march, 1865 February 2 (Box 11, Folder 1019)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; regarding friend Soule, 1865 February 4 (Box 11, Folder 1020)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; left behind with staff, 1865 February 6 (Box 11, Folder 1021)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; sending money home, 1865 February 20 (Box 11, Folder 1022)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; comments on family news, 1865 February 28 (Box 11, Folder 1023)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; comments on girls' actions, 1865 March 8 (Box 11, Folder 1024)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Mrs. Curtiss; victory at Lynchburg, 1865 March 13 (Box 11, Folder 1025)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sisters; list of changes in officers, 1865 March 16 (Box 11, Folder 1026)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; Sherman's victories, 1865 March 20 (Box 11, Folder 1027)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; Sheridan's arrival at White House, 1865 March 23 (Box 11, Folder 1028)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; map to illustrate position, 1865 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 1029)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; heavy duty, 1865 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 1030)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; description of charge, 1865 April 1 (Box 11, Folder 1031)
  - ALS, James D. Dunn to Henry A. Ward; sent copy of Shepard's Mineralogy, 1865 April 2 (Box 11, Folder 1032)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; encamped at Burkesville; Lincoln's death, 1865 April 21 (Box 11, Folder 1033)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; fatigue of company, 1865 April 28 (Box 11, Folder 1034)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; news of men in camp, 1865 May 11 (Box 11, Folder 1035)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; death of friend, 1865 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 1036)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; fears will be long time until home, 1865 June 23 (Box 11, Folder 1037)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; march toward Virginia, side of Potomac, 1865 June 27 (Box 11, Folder 1038)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; desire for mail, 1865 July 1 (Box 11, Folder 1039)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; transfer home of many men, 1865 July 8 (Box 11, Folder 1040)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; list of officers, 1865 July 23 (Box 11, Folder 1041)
  - ALS, D. Davis to Samuel Parker; copy of leave of absence signed by President Johnson, 1865 July 26 (Box 11, Folder 1042)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; lonely, fortification of Washington, 1865 July 26 (Box 11, Folder 1043)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sisters; concerning soldier friends of sisters, 1865 July 28 (Box 11, Folder 1044)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; thoughts about future, 1865 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 1045)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; activities in Washington, 1865 August 3 (Box 11, Folder 1046)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; worried about future, 1865 August 7 (Box 11, Folder 1047)
  - ALS, P. Liebiz to [Kozz], 1865 August 10 (Box 11, Folder 1048)
  - DS, Orders for transfer of hospital, Steward Charles Reiss, 1865 November 15 (Box 11, Folder 1049)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; activities after visit home, 1866 February 28 (Box 11, Folder 1050)
  - ALS, Gov. Buckingham to Mrs. Anna Gunner; regarding payment of $10, 1866 June 2 (Box 11, Folder 1051)
  - ALS, H.P. Banks to Alec Warren; request for newspapers and copy of resolution, 1866 June 30 (Box 11, Folder 1052)
  - ALS, King of Siam to Dr. Samuel House; regarding purchase of tobacco for king.(signed twice), 1866 December 20 (Box 11, Folder 1053)
  - ALS, L.M. Morrill to [Speare]; strength of certain counties and individuals, 1867 August 29 (Box 11, Folder 1054)
  - ALS, James L. Orr (Gov. of S.C.) Maj. Gen. D.E. Sickles; regret on relief of command, 1867 September 7 (Box 11, Folder 1055)
  - ALS, R.H. Tuttle to (?); farm machinery, men, 1867 September 28 (Box 11, Folder 1056)
  - ALS, Alexander Stephens to R.J. Arundel; concerning invitation to address group, 1867 November 23 (Box 11, Folder 1057)
  - ALS, Dr. Rudolph Virchow; recommendation of Berthold Riesenfeld, 1868 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 1058)
  - AMS, Charles Sumner; brief saying, 1868 November 10 (Box 11, Folder 1060)
  - ALS, David Porter to T.M. Graves; letter of introduction for Paymaster Dunn, 1868 December 6 (Box 11, Folder 1061)
  - ALS, William Sherman to General (?); returning copy of letters, 1869 January 5 (Box 12, Folder 1062)
  - ALS, Susan B. Anthony to Mrs. S.A. Underwood; articles for the "Revolution.", 1869 January 11 (Box 12, Folder 1063)
  - ALS, John Abbott to T. Apoleon Cheney; history of Marie Antoinette, 1869 February 21 (Box 12, Folder 1064)
  - ALS, Linton Stebbins to Sallie E. Thomas; sending photograph, 1869 April 26 (Box 12, Folder 1065)
  - ALS, Gen. William T. Sherman to Burnside; consolidation of the 17th and 44th armies, 1869 May 22 (Box 12, Folder 1066)
  - ALS, P.A.P. Bernam to (?); Governor's reply concerning college, 1869 June 22 (Box 12, Folder 1067)
  - ALS, Charles W. Eliot to B.A. Gould; request to act as university lecturer, 1869 December 7 (Box 12, Folder 1068)
  - ALS, Whitlow Reid to Schuyler Colfax (U.S. Vice President); regarding stories about Miss Dickinson, 1870 January 13 (Box 12, Folder 1069)
  - ALS, Edward Warren Clark to (?); International Christian Moral Science Assoc, 1870 October 19 (Box 12, Folder 1070)
  - ALS, Chas. Gounod to Monsieur Chappell (French), 1871 January 13 (Box 12, Folder 1071)
  - ALS, Chas. K. Graham to William Seward; (14 pages); various political news, 1871 February 8 (Box 12, Folder 1072)
  - ALS, Lucy Stone to Mr. Sanborn; against nomination of Harvey Jewell, 1871 July 7 (Box 12, Folder 1073)
  - ALS, E.C. Agassiz to Dr. White; certain letters and books loaned to Agassiz, 1872 November 25 (Box 12, Folder 1074)
  - ALS, Ellen Colfax to Mr. Harper; editorial in Harper's supporting husband. (Mrs. Schuyler), 1873 March 24 (Box 12, Folder 1075)
  - ALS, Gen. William Sherman to John B. Cresson; safety of Cresson's son, 1873 April 22 (Box 12, Folder 1076)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps) ward to M. Laird Simons revisions to manuscript on family, 1873 June 16 (Box 12, Folder 1077)
  - ALS, Darrin D. Porter to Doctor; congratulatory for winning over opposing party, 1873 August 3 (Box 12, Folder 1078)
  - ALS, John Jay to Henry Peter Gray; acknowledge receipt of notes, 1873 December 25 (Box 12, Folder 1079)
  - ALS, James B. Hugh to B.A. Grant(?); happy over success, 1874 June 28 (Box 12, Folder 1080)
  - ALS, John L.Dix to N. Capien; denunciation of New York Democratic Party, 1874 September 29 (Box 12, Folder 1081)
  - ALS, John Jay to Henry Peter Gray; sorry missed seeing Gray, 1875 August 23 (Box 12, Folder 1082)
  - ALS, W. Phillips to Mr. O'Brien; inventions, 1875 (Box 12, Folder 1083)
  - ALS, C.W. Williams to brother; brother's health, poor financial state, 1876 July 11 (Box 12, Folder 1084)
  - ALS, Montgomery Blair to Thomas C. Powell; Supreme Court, 1876 October 19 (Box 12, Folder 1085)
  - ALS, Prof. James D. Dana to (?); specimen of Henwoodite, 1876 November 30 (Box 12, Folder 1086)
  - ALS, A. Cleveland Coxe to G. Philip Ripley; concerning autographs, 1877 July 23 (Box 12, Folder 1087)
  - ALS, T.B. Reed to Gen. G. Fessendern; fillibustering in House, Bragg, political wheeling-dealing, 1877 December 3 (Box 12, Folder 1088)
  - ALS, James B. Angell to Mr. Newman; knowledge of James S. Haver, 1878 April 9 (Box 12, Folder 1089)
  - ALS, George F. Seymour to Bishop of Albany; unsuitable behavior of young men at General Theological Seminary, 1879 February 25 (Box 12, Folder 1090)
  - ALS, Edouard Detaille to Kingman; (French), 1879 June 28 (Box 12, Folder 1091)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to Sarah Andrews Spenser; invitation to visit, 1880 April 25 (Box 12, Folder 1092)
  - ALS, E.B. Washburn to Rifikon; possibility of meeting, 1880 June 16 (Box 12, Folder 1093)
  - ALS, Hezekiah Butterworth to Mary B. Harris; celebration of Tabernacle Feast, 1881 February 23 (Box 12, Folder 1094)
  - ALS, Justin Winsor to Col. Rolfe; regarding memorial history of Boston, 1881 November 24 (Box 12, Folder 1095)
  - ALS, Philip Brooks to Miss Devereux; new church at Marshfield, 1882 January 3 (Box 12, Folder 1096)
  - ALS, Richard Caulfield to Rev. Pres. Noah Porter; sending books and information for library, 1882 February 8 (Box 12, Folder 1097)
  - ALS, James B. Angell to Cliabin; college affairs, University of Michigan, 1882 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 1098)
  - ALS, N.B. Fremont to Mrs. Pratt; request packages sent, 1882 July 3 (Box 12, Folder 1099)
  - ALS, L.P. Morton to O.C. Gardiner; no job opening for daughter as correspondent, 1882 August 14 (Box 12, Folder 1100)
  - ALS, Commander A.T. Mahan to Rear Admiral T.H. Stevens; preparing chronicles of naval battles in war, 1883 May 20 (Box 12, Folder 1101)
  - ALS, M.R. Waite to H.A. Spaulding; congratulatory, trip with Sherman, 1883 August 5 (Box 12, Folder 1102)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to Mrs. Isaac W. England; cannot accept invitation, 1884 February 8 (Box 12, Folder 1103)
  - ALS, Phillips Brooks to Edward Everett Hale; admission of divorced woman to communion, 1884 March 6 (Box 12, Folder 1104)
  - ALS, James G. Blaine to Stetson Hutchins; sympathy on death of wife, 1884 April 27 (Box 12, Folder 1105)
  - ALS, Saint-Gaudens, Augustus to Bailin [?]; no pressure on agreement between two, 1884 July 9 (Box 12, Folder 1106)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to B.F. Underwood; Dr. Patton's sermon, 1885 February 12 (Box 12, Folder 1107)
  - ALS, Arthur Hadley to Albert Thorndike; possible future book, 1885 April 15 (Box 12, Folder 1108)
  - ALS, T.F. Bayard to D. Duncan; filling an empty office, 1885 June 19 (Box 12, Folder 1109)
  - ALS, S.J. Tilden to Mr. Manning; harbor defences, silver question, 1885 November 14 (Box 12, Folder 1110)
  - ALS, Frederick A.P. Barnard (Pres. of Columbia College) to Gen. Adam Badeau; comment on public affairs, 1886 January 22 (Box 12, Folder 1111)
  - ALS, L.O.C. Lamar to Mr. Endicott; decline invitation to reception, 1886 February 3 (Box 12, Folder 1112)
  - ALS, P.W. Peckham to Mrs. Paul Manning; New York Supreme Court, 1886 March 29 (Box 12, Folder 1113)
  - ALS, H. Campbell Bannerman to Lord Mount-Temple; appointment to medical officer, 1886 April 20 (Box 12, Folder 1114)
  - ALS, P.W. Peckham to Mrs. Paul Manning; regarding husband's actions, 1886 April 30 (Box 12, Folder 1115)
  - ALS, [?] to W. Johnson Witalbacker; U.S. Legation, 1886 May 16 (Box 12, Folder 1116)
  - ALS. P.L. Lavant to Mr. Manning; raise $4,000 with Angus stock, 1886 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 1117)
  - ALS, Augustus Saint-Gaudens to Prof. Maynard; arranging meeting with Mr. Garnett, 1886 September 10 (Box 12, Folder 1118)
  - ALS, Alphonso Taft to Jacob Schalkenstein; autograph request, 1887 March 31 (Box 12, Folder 1119)
  - ALS, Augustus Saint-Gaudens to Mr. Clarke; misunderstanding with Mr. Storey over money, 1887 April 3 (Box 12, Folder 1120)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to Mrs. Underwood; copies of The Woman's Journal, 1887 May (Box 12, Folder 1121)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to Underwood [?]; questions why articles not published, 1887 December 1 (Box 12, Folder 1122)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to friend; comments on paper, 1887 December 18 (Box 12, Folder 1123)
  - ALS, J. Massenet to brother; decline invitation to dine, 1888 February 4 (Box 12, Folder 1124)
  - ALS, Phillips Brooks to William Richmond; request for information on father, l888 April 17 (Box 12, Folder 1125)
  - ALS, Henry C. Bower to Benjamin Harrison; congratulatory--nomination, 1888 June 25 (Box 12, Folder 1126)
  - ALS, T.F. Bayard to E. Phelps; social activities in Washington, 1889 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 1127)
  - ALS, George F. Hoar to Mr. Whitney; sympathy-death of father, 1889 March 1 (Box 12, Folder 1128)
  - ALS, C.A. Dana to Mr. Harvier; Harrison vs. Cleveland administration, 1889 June 20 (Box 12, Folder 1129)
  - ALS, James H. Wilson to John C. Rofes; asks for letter of introduction, 1890 July 10 (Box 12, Folder 1130)
  - ALS, L.P. Lathrop to William [?]; controversy over certain passage in writing, 1890 October 3 (Box 12, Folder 1131)
  - ALS, Augustus Saint- Gaudens to Mr. Clarke; request for forwarding letter, 1890 October 25 (Box 12, Folder 1132)
  - ALS, Mrs. P.T. Barnum to Henry Hale; thanks for check, compliments on article, 1891 November 19 (Box 12, Folder 1133)
  - ALS, John La Fargo to Mr. Horne; sickness, 1892 April 5 (Box 12, Folder 1134)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Cady Stanton to John B. Thacher; concerning work on woman suffrage, 1892 December 11 (Box 12, Folder 1135)
  - ALS, John La Farge to Ch. W. Hoddard; old friend from France, 1894 January 10 (Box 12, Folder 1136)
  - ALS, Joseph H. Choate to Henry G. Bowen; decline invitation to Woodstock, 1894 March 20 (Box 12, Folder 1137)
  - ALS, George Glenn to Col. John H. James; description of duties, 1895 January 3 (Box 12, Folder 1138)
  - TLS, George E. Glenn to Col. John H. James.; thanks for letter concerning Brice, 1895 January 24 (Box 12, Folder 1139)
  - ALS, Thomas Bayard (ambassador) to Henry Woodward; decline dinner invitation (enclosed biography and card of Bayard), 1895 January 30 (Box 12, Folder 1140)
  - ALS, Lt. P. Finley to John James; will send twelve copies of magazine, 1895 February 16 (Box 12, Folder 1141)
  - TLS, James Burns to John James; regarding article in United States Service Magazine, 1895 February 20 (Box 12, Folder 1142)
  - ALS, P. Finley to John H. James; sending copies by mail, 1895 February 23 (Box 12, Folder 1143)
  - The United Service Magazine, including article by John H. James., 1894 October (Box 12, Folder 1144)
  - ALS, Jules Massenet to [?]; congratulatory--receiving role, 1895 June 5 (Box 12, Folder 1145)
  - ALS, Rose Elizabeth Cleveland (sister of Grover Cleveland) to cousin; Florence, Italy, 1896 January 1 (Box 12, Folder 1146)
  - ALS, Jules Breton to Knoedler; (French), 1896 January 7 (Box 12, Folder 1147)
  - ALS, Adm. R. W. Meade to A.L. Batcheler; recollections of President Lincoln, 1896 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 1148)
  - ALS, Amanda Douglas to Youth's Companion editor; submits manuscript, 1896 May 7 (Box 12, Folder 1149)
  - ALS, T. F. Bayard to Sir N.H. Flower; structure of Whales, 1896 September 17 (Box 12, Folder 1150)
  - ALS, Miriam Florence Leslie to Massett; description of stay and her activities, 1897 January 26 (Box 12, Folder 1151)
  - ALS, Camille St.Saens to (?); (French), 1897 February (Box 12, Folder 1152)
  - DS, Captured captain's commission in Philippine Rebel Army, 1898 August 24 (Box 12, Folder 1153)
  - DS, Official edict signed by President Don Emilio Aguinaldo of Philippines, 1899 January 19 (Box 12, Folder 1154)
  - ALS, A.T. Mahan to W.H. Ridenig; question on request for article on Farragut, 1899 February 1 (Box 12, Folder 1155)
  - DS, Edict signed by Emilio Aguinaldo, President of the Philippines, 1899 February 3 (Box 12, Folder 1156)
  - ADS, List of men in batallion, (Philippines?) (Spanish), 1899 May 27 (Box 16)
  - DS, Pass signed by Mayor of Capital for John Goodward (Philippines), 1899 August 17 (Box 12, Folder 1158)
  - TLS, Whitelaw Reid to Cushman Davis (chairman of Senate Committee on Foreign Relations); Chinese problem, 1900 July 20 (Box 13, Folder 1159)
  - ALS, Joseph Choate to S.L. Thorndike; death of Williamson, 1903 August 19 (Box 13, Folder 1160)
  - ALS, J. Choate to S.L. Thorndike; account of Williamson for Colonial Society, 1903 September 26 (Box 13, Folder 1161)
  - TLS, Richard Peary to R.H. Lyman; lecture on Arctic work, 1907 February 3 (Box 13, Folder 1162)
  - ALS, A.T. Mahan to James Carleton Young; criticism of attitude toward authors, 1908 April 28 (Box 13, Folder 1163)
  - ALS, John S. Sargent to Livermore; looking foward to dinner, seeing Urn, 1912 March 29 (Box 13, Folder 1164)
  - TDS, Theodore Roosevelt; recommendation for book by O'Laughlin (his Asst Sec'y of State), 1916 May 10 (Box 13, Folder 1165)
  - ALS, Elijah Coffin to George Knollenberg; concerning father, Charles Fisher Coffin, 1916 August 22 (Box 13, Folder 1166)
  - ALS, Bayard to Att'y General; congratulations for fight against profiteers, 1919 August 30 (Box 13, Folder 1167)
  - ALS, William Beebe to Mrs. Claphaur; concerning Caddis flies, 1924 February 14 (Box 13, Folder 1168)
  - ALS, John Singer Sargent to Mr. B.;concerning 12 pieces of war exhibit, 1924 May 9 (Box 13, Folder 1169)
  - TLS, Thomas Mott Osborne to Mr. Leach; strong statement against American Japanese immigration policy, 1924 July 28 (Box 13, Folder 1170)
  - ALS, Havelock Ellis to Mr. Ellis (?); invitation to visit while in England, 1925 August 15 (Box 13, Folder 1171)
  - TM, E.E. Exon, "History of the White Water Canal, Indiana"; Photostatic Copy, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 1172)
  - ALS, Charles Beard to Mrs. Knollenberg; thanks for letter, 1939 August 30 (Box 13, Folder 1173)
  - TLS, Franklin D. Roosevelt to Bernhard Knollenberg; thanks for copy of Yale University Library Gazette, 1940 January 17 (Box 13, Folder 1174)
  - ALS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; regarding Langer, 1940 January 21 (Box 13, Folder 1175)
  - TLS, Jay N. Darling to Bernard Knollenberg; wishes Knollenberg to choose cartoons he wants, 1940 August 8 (Box 13, Folder 1176)
  - TLS, Jay N. Darling to Bernhard Knollenberg; regrets that original cartoon already given away, 1940 September 17 (Box 13, Folder 1177)
  - TLS, Jay N. Darling (J.N. Ding) to Bernhard Knollenberg; regarding "A Tough Old Oak" (cartoon), 1940 September 26 (Box 13, Folder 1178)
  - TLS, Jay N. Darling to Bernhard Knollenberg; cartoon given away before request came, 1940 October 10 (Box 13, Folder 1179)
  - TLS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; thanks for contribution for Anti-Fascist Fund, 1941 April 24 (Box 13, Folder 1180)
  - TLS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; start of new book on Americans "worthy of note.", 1941 May 29 (Box 13, Folder 1181)
  - TLS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; regarding propsed dinner, 1941 June 9 (Box 13, Folder 1182)
  - ALS, Charles Beard to Bernard Knollenberg; accept offer of Library, 1941 July 2 (Box 13, Folder 1183)
  - ALS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; proposed bookplate, 1941 July 12 (Box 13, Folder 1184)
  - ALS, Charles Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; contribution to Library Fund, 1941 July 21 (Box 13, Folder 1185)
  - TLS, Charles A. Beard to Bernhard Knollenberg; request for volume by Thomas Mann, 1942 June 20 (Box 13, Folder 1186)
  - ALS, Charles A. Beard to Mr. Babb; thanks for Mann volume, 1942 June 29 (Box 13, Folder 1187)
  - TLS, Edward R. Stettinius to Bernard Knollenberg; submits copy of report to President on Lend- Lease, 1943 December 11 (Box 13, Folder 1188)
  - ALS, L.G. Bullfinch to Rev. B. Whitman; Unitarian Church, undated (Box 13, Folder 1189)
  - ALS, Daniel Dulany to Charles Carroll; regarding patents, land, courts, undated (Box 13, Folder 1190)
  - AMS, S.L. Frey; narrative account of history of the West and Philip R. Frey, undated (Box 13, Folder 1191)
  - ALS, S.M. (Fuller) Ossali to Elizabeth Peabody (Salem); ending of letter, undated (Box 13, Folder 1192)
  - Biographical sketch of Elias Jackson ("Lucky") Baldwin (1828-1909); Harry O. Garman, undated (Box 13, Folder 1193)
  - ALS, A.V. Humboldt to Councillor Mendelssohn; requests visit, undated (Box 13, Folder 1194)
  - ALS, Baron Alexander Humboldt to [?]; requests translation into English of, letter of recommendation, undated (Box 13, Folder 1195)
  - AL, John Johns to nieces; advice and inspiration, undated (Box 13, Folder 1196)
  - ALS, (Fragment) Ernest Charles Jones to [?], undated (Box 13, Folder 1197)
  - ALS, John La Fargo to Mr. Stoddard; letter of introduction for son-in-law, undated (Box 13, Folder 1198)
  - ALS, P.B. Macaulay to Mrs. Malcom; regrets cannot join party, undated (Box 13, Folder 1199)
  - ALS, Jean Frederic Philippeaux Maurepas to [?]; La Grange (in French), November 9 (Box 13, Folder 1200)
  - ALS, (Fragment) Isaac Parker (Chief Justice of Massachusetts) to [?], undated (Box 13, Folder 1201)
  - ALS, John Penn to [?]; request to visit at another time, undated (Box 13, Folder 1202)
  - ALS, J. Pierpont (Grandfather of J. Pierpont Morgan) to Mr. Capon; discussion of knowledge, consciousness, undated (Box 13, Folder 1203)
  - ALS, John Singer Sargent to Sir Georg Henschel; regarding portrait of Sir Georg.(2 letters) (Memo concerning probable dates), undated (Box 13, Folder 1204)
  - ALS, Governor William Shirley to Treasurer; request meeting, undated (Box 13, Folder 1205)
  - ADS, Gov. William Shirley; list of officers of Garrison of Cape Breton, undated (Box 13, Folder 1206)
  - ALS, W. Temple to Samuel White; wishes for good health, undated (Box 13, Folder 1207)